Support Admin Watch on kissasia.cam or kisskh.org
دعم المشرف شاهد على kissasia.cam أو kisskh.org
San'er Ge
سانير جي
Digging graves and ginseng like this
حفر القبور والجينسنغ مثل هذا
We're breaking a major taboo here
نحن نكسر أحد المحرمات الكبرى هنا
Is it worth risking so much for this?
هل يستحق الأمر المخاطرة بهذا القدر من أجل هذا؟
Did you eat chicken crap before coming out?
هل أكلت فضلات الدجاج قبل الخروج؟
Why are you chattering so much?
لماذا تتحدث كثيرا؟
San'er Ge
سانير جي
What's going on?
ماذا يحدث هنا؟
San'er Ge, San'er Ge
سانير جي، سانير جي
You scared me
لقد اخافتني
Are you okay, Ge?
هل انت بخير يا جي؟
Ge, are you alright?
جي هل أنت بخير؟
Bring the torch over
أحضر الشعلة
What's the most sinister thing in these northern woods?
ما هو الشيء الأكثر شرا في هذه الغابات الشمالية؟
What is it, Ge?
ما الأمر يا جي؟
That would be Ginseng Taiye and Fox Three Tainai
سيكون هذا جينسنغ تايي وفوكس ثري تايناي
Let me tell you two
دعني أخبرك اثنين
Especially the ginseng spirits in these woods
وخاصة أرواح الجينسنغ في هذه الغابات
You have to be extra careful
يجب عليك أن تكون حذرا للغاية
If you run into a reanimated corpse
إذا صادفت جثة أعيد إحيائها
You're in real trouble
أنت في ورطة حقيقية
Grab your weapons
إمسك أسلحتك
San'er Ge
سانير جي
Is The Nine Immortals' Compass really that mystical?
هل بوصلة التسعة الخالدين حقا غامضة؟
Just one touch from you
لمسة واحدة منك فقط
And the Ginseng King reveals its location
ويكشف ملك الجينسنغ عن مكانه
Sounds pretty far-fetched to me
يبدو الأمر بعيد المنال بالنسبة لي
Nonsense
هراء
Ever since the Jin family was wiped out
منذ أن تم القضاء على عائلة جين
They were buried beneath the Mountain God Temple
لقد دُفنوا تحت معبد إله الجبل
That compass
تلك البوصلة
It's the only treasure that can find the Ginseng King
إنه الكنز الوحيد الذي يمكن العثور عليه من قبل ملك الجينسنغ
Every major family envies it
كل عائلة كبيرة تحسده
Let me tell you two
دعني أخبرك اثنين
If we find the Ginseng King
إذا وجدنا ملك الجينسنغ
Forget just the ginseng trade in Songling Town
انسَ تجارة الجينسنغ في بلدة سونغلينغ
We could buy up all of Northeast China
يمكننا شراء كل شمال شرق الصين
I saw them take their last breath myself
لقد رأيتهم يأخذون أنفاسهم الأخيرة بنفسي
Dead as can be
ميت كما يمكن أن يكون
It ran off
لقد هرب
The ginseng spirit ran off
روح الجينسنغ هربت
Where did it go?
أين ذهب؟
Ma Lian
ما ليان
Stick your pole down there
ضع عمودك هناك
What is that thing?
ما هو هذا الشيء؟
Don't touch it
لا تلمسه
San'er Ge
سانير جي
Do you think we've run into a Jin family corpse?
هل تعتقد أننا صادفنا جثة عائلة جين؟
That mouth of yours
هذا فمك
Is like an old lady's padded pants
مثل سروال مبطن لسيدة عجوز
Look at you two, such cowards
انظروا إليكما، أيها الجبناء
Did you forget your manhood at home?
هل نسيت رجولتك في البيت؟
A bird scared you two like that
لقد أخافكما طائر مثل هذا
This...
هذا...
Run
يجري
Why is this crow acting possessed too?
لماذا هذا الغراب يتصرف وكأنه مسكون أيضاً؟
How is it, Ma Lian?
كيف حالك ما ليان؟
It's nothing serious
ليس هناك شيء خطير
San'er Ge
سانير جي
Is this the path up the mountain?
هل هذا هو الطريق إلى الجبل؟
San'er Ge, San'er Ge
سانير جي، سانير جي
This is bad
هذا سيء
Spirit Wall
جدار الروح
Now we're in trouble
الآن نحن في ورطة
I told you so
لقد قلت لك ذلك
You can't disturb the soil of the Jin Family Ancestral Tomb
لا يمكنك إزعاج تربة مقبرة عائلة جين الأجداد
Five Elements Cycle
دورة العناصر الخمسة
Earth creates metal
الأرض تخلق المعدن
Digging up soil on their ancestral tomb
حفر التربة على قبر أسلافهم
This... this...
هذا...هذا...
Aren't we digging up their roots?
ألسنا نقتلع جذورهم؟
My element is fire
عنصري هو النار
It overcomes metal
يتغلب على المعدن
Ma Lian
ما ليان
Where is he?
أين هو؟
Oh my god
يا إلهي
Sorry for any offense today
آسف على أي إساءة اليوم
Please forgive me
رجائاً أعطني
I'll burn extra incense for you tomorrow
سأحرق لك بخورًا إضافيًا غدًا
From today on
من اليوم فصاعدا
I'm your grandson now
أنا حفيدك الآن
You're my grandpa
أنت جدي
Is this a trick or a real deal?
هل هذه خدعة أم حقيقة؟
If it's real
إذا كان حقيقيا
Throw out a vine
رمي الكرمة
On the open road
على الطريق المفتوح
We each go our own way
كل واحد منا يذهب في طريقه الخاص
No matter which path you take today
بغض النظر عن المسار الذي تتخذه اليوم
You'll die either way
سوف تموت في كلتا الحالتين
Three taboos for digging ginseng in the mountains
ثلاثة محظورات لحفر الجينسنغ في الجبال
Don't dig up graves
لا تحفروا القبور
Don't disrespect your ancestors
لا تسيء إلى أسلافك
Don't offend the mountain god
لا تسيء إلى إله الجبل
You've broken so many taboos
لقد كسرت الكثير من المحرمات
You should've been dead long ago
كان ينبغي أن تموت منذ زمن طويل
Heaven kept you alive till now
لقد أبقتك السماء على قيد الحياة حتى الآن
Just so I, your grandpa
فقط حتى انا جدك
Could finish you off myself
يمكنني أن أنهيك بنفسي
You're a Jin
أنت جين
I'm not the one who killed your family
أنا لست من قتل عائلتك
Spare me
انقذني
My name is Jin Shisan
اسمي جين شيسان
I grew up with my foster father Jin Buhuan
لقد نشأت مع والدي بالتبني جين بوهوان
Raised in the Changbai Ginseng Guild
نشأ في نقابة تشانغباي جينسنغ
My foster father Jin Buhuan
والدي بالتبني جين بوهوان
Is the top leader of the Changbai Ginseng Guild
هو الزعيم الأعلى لنقابة تشانغباي جينسنغ
All these years
كل هذه السنوات
The guild has been full of rivalry and greed
لقد كانت النقابة مليئة بالتنافس والجشع
A mix of all sorts
مزيج من كل الأنواع
Though my foster father is the leader
على الرغم من أن والدي بالتبني هو الزعيم
He's avoided guild affairs for years
لقد تجنب شؤون النقابة لسنوات
Living deep in the mountains
العيش في أعماق الجبال
Three years ago
منذ ثلاث سنوات
My foster father suddenly decided to join
قرر والدي بالتبني الانضمام فجأة
The Grand Mountain Assembly held every three years
جمعية الجبل الكبير تعقد كل ثلاث سنوات
My sister and I
أنا وأختي
Begged to go along and see the world
توسلت للذهاب ورؤية العالم
Alright
على ما يرام
Eat quickly, it's still hot
تناول الطعام بسرعة، فهو لا يزال ساخنًا
Okay
تمام
Here
هنا
I want that piece
أريد تلك القطعة
Take this one, it's bigger
خذ هذا، إنه أكبر
Alright, alright
حسنا حسنا
It's really beautiful
إنه جميل حقا
Use it for protection
استخدمه للحماية
Thanks, Ge
شكرا لك، جي
Okay
تمام
Master Yuan, the time has come
سيد يوان، لقد حان الوقت
Can we begin the ritual and invite the gods?
هل يمكننا أن نبدأ الطقوس وندعو الآلهة؟
Thanks to the blessing of Grandmaster Sun Liang
بفضل نعمة الأستاذ الكبير صن ليانغ
Today, our Changbai Ginseng Guild
اليوم، جمعية تشانغباي جينسنغ الخاصة بنا
All thirty-two families have gathered here
لقد اجتمعت هنا كل العائلات الاثنين والثلاثين
To enter the temple and invite the gods
للدخول إلى المعبد ودعوة الآلهة
To start the mountain harvest
لبدء حصاد الجبل
Fate and fortune keep turning
القدر والحظ يستمران في التحول
Every ten years brings a change
كل عشر سنوات يجلب التغيير
This year, the Nine Immortals are yang
هذا العام، الخالدون التسعة هم يانغ
So the Lead Immortal
لذا فإن القائد الخالد
Is male
هل هو ذكر
I nominate Jin Buhuan of the Jin family as Lead Immortal
أرشح جين بوهوان من عائلة جين ليكون القائد الخالد
Who agrees?
من يوافق؟
Who objects?
من يعترض؟
Since no one objects,
وبما أنه لا أحد يعترض،
let's proceed as planned.
دعونا نستمر كما هو مخطط.
The following Jin Family Eight Immortals
عائلة جين الثمانية الخالدون التاليون
those named will follow the Lead Immortal into the temple to invite the spirits.
سوف يتبع هؤلاء المذكورون القائد الخالد إلى المعبد لدعوة الأرواح.
The top three immortals: Jin Lizhong,
أفضل ثلاثة خالدين: جين ليزونغ،
Good, good, good.
جيد، جيد، جيد.
Jin Chengwei,
جين تشينغوي,
Jin Yulan.
جين يولان.
Good.
جيد.
That was the first time my sister and I
كانت تلك المرة الأولى التي ألتقي فيها بأختي وأنا
had seen such a grand occasion.
لقد رأيت مثل هذه المناسبة العظيمة.
We heard the cheers and applause from the crowd below.
سمعنا هتافات وتصفيق من الحشد أدناه.
Lead Immortal, please.
كن خالدا من فضلك.
My heart was also filled with excitement.
وكان قلبي أيضًا مليئًا بالإثارة.
That day, my foster father's face was very serious.
في ذلك اليوم، كان وجه والدي بالتبني جديًا للغاية.
He hesitated a little as he stood up.
تردد قليلا عندما وقف.
I thought inviting the spirits was a major event.
اعتقدت أن دعوة الأرواح كانت حدثًا كبيرًا.
That's why he was so cautious.
ولهذا السبب كان حذرا للغاية.
My foster father led the uncles and aunts
كان والدي بالتبني يقود أعمامي وخالاتي
up to the altar.
حتى المذبح.
Every step was taken slowly,
لقد تم اتخاذ كل خطوة ببطء،
as if something weighed down their feet.
وكأن شيئاً يثقل أقدامهم.
So heavy, they could barely move.
كانت ثقيلة جدًا، حتى أنهم لم يتمكنوا من التحرك.
The uncles' positions were arranged in advance.
لقد تم ترتيب مواقف الأعمام مسبقًا.
Everyone stood in their assigned spots.
وقف الجميع في أماكنهم المخصصة.
At the hall entrance, my foster father led
عند مدخل القاعة، قادني والدي بالتبني
and bowed deeply.
وانحنى بعمق.
After that,
بعد ذلك،
he led everyone slowly into the main hall.
قاد الجميع ببطء إلى القاعة الرئيسية.
Who could have imagined
من كان يتصور
that from this moment on,
أنه من هذه اللحظة فصاعدا،
I would lose all my family.
سأفقد عائلتي بأكملها.
Don't kill me!
لا تقتلني!
No!
لا!
Scatter the five grains.
نثر الحبوب الخمس.
First, scatter to the east, Jia and Yi wood.
أولاً، قم بالتشتت نحو الشرق، خشب جيا ويي.
From now on, every branch will prosper.
ومن الآن فصاعدا، كل فرع سوف يزدهر.
Second, scatter to the south, Bing and Ding fire.
ثانياً، التشتت نحو الجنوب، بينج ودينج يطلقان النار.
Descendants in every branch will thrive.
سوف يزدهر الأحفاد في كل فرع.
Third, scatter to the four directions, Geng and Xin metal.
ثالثا، تشتت إلى الاتجاهات الأربعة، جينج وشين المعادن.
Descendants will gain great fortune.
سوف يحصل الأحفاد على ثروة كبيرة.
Fourth, scatter to the north, Ren and Gui water.
رابعا، تشتت نحو الشمال، مياه رين وجوي.
Gold, pearls, and treasures will pile up.
الذهب واللؤلؤ والكنوز سوف تتراكم.
Fifth, scatter to the center, Wu and Ji earth.
خامسا، تشتت إلى المركز، وو وجي الأرض.
Descendants will be wealthy and live long.
وسوف يكون الأحفاد أغنياء ويعيشون طويلاً.
Jin Family disciples, open the Immortal Gate.
تلاميذ عائلة جين، افتحوا بوابة الخلود.
Mountain God, guide us to the ginseng spot.
إله الجبل، أرشدنا إلى مكان الجينسنغ.
Nine Immortals, show the way.
التسعة الخالدون، أظهروا الطريق.
Three and four, heaven and earth.
ثلاثة وأربعة، السماء والأرض.
Seven and five, the shoulders.
سبعة وخمسة، الأكتاف.
Six and one, the waists.
ستة وواحد، الخصر.
Two and nine, the feet.
اثنان وتسعة، الأقدام.
Eight is the central palace.
ثمانية هو القصر المركزي.
Open.
يفتح.